(upbeat music)
♪ In the not too
distant future ♪
♪ Somewhere in time and space ♪
♪ Mike Nelson and
his robot pals ♪
♪ Are caught in
an endless chase ♪
♪ Pursued by a woman ♪
♪ Whose name is Pearl ♪
♪ An evil gal who wants
to rule the world ♪
♪ She threw a few
things in her purse ♪
♪ And in her rocket ship ♪
♪ She hunts him all
across the universe ♪
- [Pearl] I'll get you!
♪ I'll send him cheesy movies ♪
♪ The worst I can find ♪
♪ La la la ♪
♪ He'll have to sit
and watch them all ♪
♪ And I'll monitor his mind ♪
♪ Now keep in mind ♪
♪ Mike can't control ♪
♪ When the movies begin or end ♪
♪ La la la ♪
♪ He'll try to keep his sanity ♪
♪ With the help of
his robot friends ♪
♪ Robot roll call ♪
♪ Cambot ♪
- You're on.
♪ Gypsy ♪
♪ Tom Servo ♪
- Check me out.
♪ Crow ♪
♪ If you're wondering how
he eats and breathes ♪
♪ And other science facts ♪
♪ La la la ♪
♪ Just repeat to yourself ♪
♪ It's just a show ♪
♪ I should really just relax ♪
♪ For Mystery Science
Theatre 3000 ♪
(doors creaking and closing)
- Hi everyone, welcome to
the Satellite of Love here.
- Hi.
- Probably wondering
what's up with Crow here.
Well, I'll let him
explain, go ahead.
- Explain what?
Oh yeah, the nest.
Yeah, it turns out
that the top of my head
provides a perfect nesting
site for the rare Spix's macaw.
I've known that for some time,
but this is the first year
I've had an actual
brooding mother.
- See, what I don't get
is how you cannot notice
them building a nest on
the top or your head.
- Well, I was aware of
some activity, Mike.
But you know, it's
the top of my head.
I suppose you know every
detail at all times
of everything happening
at the top of your head?
- I guess not.
- Yeah.
- When does that
one hatch anyway?
- Well, pretty soon, Mike.
It's been three weeks and
to tell you the truth,
I'll be a little relieved.
The Spix's macaw is
not a small bird.
So when the mother's actually
here, sitting on my head
with that brooding
spot, all pink and warm.
There's no feathers,
it just, whoa, whoa.
Here she comes again.
(bird squawking)
Damn, another one.
- Great. We'll be right back.
- Mike, would you
mind doing this one?
I feel like I've done my
part for the Spix's macaw.
- Well, you're the one with
the perfect nesting site head.
(Crow sighs)
(upbeat music)
- [Crow] Ack.
Get away, you rebel.
Cease and desist.
Back, I say.
Okay then, you mongrels.
(gun shotsbanging)
(laughing) Eat it.
- Crow, everything all right?
- Oh yeah, I had a little
weasel problem there, Mike.
They were trying to steal
my poor little eggs.
I never knew weasels
could be such weasels.
- Pearl's goons are calling.
Yellow?
- What, do you
want a little more?
- No.
- All right, Sporto.
This time, you are
one dead monkey.
One, two, three. (grunts)
Oh god.
All right, best out of 99, then.
- Oh, hello, disturbingly
unhairy ones. (laughing)
The lovely Pearl is still gone.
- Yay!
- Wee, woo hoo!
- Yes.
- Oh yeah, that's a shame.
- Dog gonnit.
- Really.
- But stay tuned for this
important message from her.
Okay, rubber arms, back to work.
- Yes.
(keypad beeping)
Accessing satellite
relay to Los Angeles.
Come in, Pearl.
Pearl, come in.
Pearl, come in, can you read me?
- Calm down, brainiac.
Yeah, hi, everyone.
I flew the van out here
to LA to try and find
some more movies to
torture you guys with.
Thought I'd consult an expert.
So I took and went and
gone and got this guy here,
from Entertainment Tonight.
- Hello, Mike.
Hello, small robots.
How can I help?
- Leonard Maltin?
Pearl, you are connected, whew.
- Excuse me, Mister
Maltin, what do you make
of the stylistic
resurgence of Italian
neo-realist filmmaking in the
vein of De Sica's Umberto D?
- Yeah, Maltin.
Is it true their working
on yet another remake
of "The Fish That
Saved Pittsburgh?"
- Oh, yeah, yeah.
- Stop bugging Mr.
Siskel with questions.
- Maltin.
- He's helping me.
So, what do you
recommend, Roger?
- Leonard.
I'd highly recommend the
1961 monster movie, "Gorgo."
It's sort of a British
take on the Godzilla thing.
- Mr. Maltin, is
"Gorgo" really that bad?
I mean, you're not really
gonna hurt us, are ya?
- Well, that's a matter
of opinion, Mike.
Now, I actually like Gorgo.
But when we reviewed
it for my number one
best selling movie
and video guide,
it put two of my assistant
editors into intensive care.
So who knows?
Besides, Pearl promised me
a light lunch at Skybar.
- No.
I said one appetizer
only, Ebert.
- Maltin.
- Okay, Mr. Maltin Ebert.
Don't push your luck or it's
a small decaf at Starbucks.
- Well.
- Brainguy.
- Oh, yes Pearl?
Do you mind?
- Please, not at all.
(eerie music)
- Okay.
And go.
(grunts)
- Hey Crow, your eggs are gone.
- Oh yeah, they got taken away
by egg protective services.
I accidentally made an
omelet in front of them.
Kinda spooked 'em.
- Yeah, well, I hope
you get to visit.
(alarm blaring)
- Oh, we got movie time!
- Curse you, Maltin!
(doors creaking and thudding)
- Wow.
- Right down here.
- (murmuring) London, England.
Yeah, which is paid
for by exorbitant taxes
on Rod Stewart
and Pete Townsend.
- [Tom] Wait, I just
got three words into it.
- What a terrible
name for a movie.
- The vice president's
unimaginative campaign slogan.
- Good masonry
work on the titles.
- Yeah it was done by the guys
at Mark Seven Productions.
- [Tom] Aww.
♪ Oh Gorgo boy, the
gore, the gore is going ♪
♪ From gore to gore ♪
- Fa Young loves Fa Young.
- You know, name your
kid Muir Mathieson,
he's pretty much destined to
conduct the Sinfonia of London.
- The lost stooge.
- Yeah, yeah, and
all these other goons
from the sceptered isle.
♪ Down with the
old folks at home ♪
- Who's Paul Robison?
Lovely.
- Hawaii 5-0 use to have
really different credits.
- Frank King, Maurice King.
- Administration.
- [Mike] Did Frank
sneak in afterwards
and put that little dig
under Maurice's name?
- I think that ship's PC
valve is a little off there.
- Without a hard tack!
- Poop Deck Pappy,
the real story.
- Sam, it's looking
terrible ugly.
- [Tom] Well thanks a lot.
- The men are getting edgy.
- Yeah, so am I.
- [Crow] Need any freelance
frog matting services?
- Come on Joe, make
it snappy will ya?
Come on, let's get outta here.
- Now wait a minute Sam.
There's thousands of
dollars worth of stuff
in that old rust bucket.
I'm not getting outta
here without it.
- Are you kiddin'?
- [Tom] We have to go
find Robert Denbey.
- [Man] Stop worrying.
I'll stake it out and be
back up in 10 minutes.
- [Crow] I should moisturize.
- [Mike] I think the
pool guy over-chlorinated
the ocean here.
- [Tom] Oh, this new
cool ranch flavored
scuba air isn't very good.
- [Crow] The legendary lost
treasure of Captain Crunch.
- [Tom] Oh look,
he carries his own
little expresso machine
on his back with him.
- [Crow] Somebody's got
to get on the other side
of that boat or we're
in trouble, guys.
- [Man] He's been
down half an hour.
- I know these waters well Sam.
I've never seen the
like of this before.
- [Mike] Just puts
my hate out of shape.
- Get me a lung.
I'm going down to get him.
He's come up!
- [Tom] I put the propane
tanks on by mistake!
(eerie music)
- [Crow] It's Robert
Maxwell, he's alive!
- [Man] Move it forward, Derek!
- [Mike] Our game of Risk!
- [Crow] Mike, Servo,
for what it's worth,
my heart will go on.
- [Mike] Good.
- [Crow] Okay.
- [Mike] You know, when
this boat was launched,
it was promoted as
pretty damn sinkable.
- [Tom] The HMS Over-Easy.
- [Crow] Yeah, it's rough.
But is it really too
rough to feed us?
- [Mike] I'm
drowning and I'm wet.
- [Tom] Gary, I'm steering!
- [Mike] Great, now our
toothpick sculpture.
- [Tom] Let go!
- [Mike] Man, this is
worse than when Australia
formed right next to us.
- [Crow] Don't worry, sir,
turns out Shelly Winters
is a very good swimmer.
- [Mike] And?
Oh, they're fine.
♪ They got into port ♪
♪ And everyone was okay ♪
♪ They went out for
lunch and felt better ♪
- [Tom] Hey, Mike Nelson.
- [Mike] Hey, Tom Servo.
- [Tom] No, I mean...
Nevermind.
Dummy.
- [Mike] Why?
Well, I'm sure it's fine.
I don't know much about
propellers anyway.
- [Tom] I guess I
shouldn't have thrown
the captain's hat overboard.
He wasn't pleased.
- [Crow] Well, there's
water in the basement.
The carpet's all ruined.
- Not as bad as I thought, Joe.
- [Joe] How long to
get her into shape.
- Rutter stock's bent,
couple of sprung plates.
- [Joe] Uh-huh.
- At best on deck,
three or four days.
- And we're out of fresh water.
- [Mike] We'll have to
drink concentrate, then.
- Let's go ashore and see
what they've got, eh Sam?
- [Tom] Yes, let's put on
some Old Spice and go ashore.
(Tom whistling)
- [Crow] There's dead
cows in the water.
- Look there.
- [Tom] A tuna
swallowed an armadillo.
- I've never seen
anything like that before.
- [Mike] Some kind of sealecanth
death cult or something,
I don't know.
- [Tom] Let's sell it to
the Japanese for $60.000.
- The whole ocean bottom
must of been torn up.
- [Crow] Ick, can I wipe
on your jacket, please?
- [Mike] Wow, new island
got settled very quickly.
- [Crow] Yeah.
- [Tom] Lice for sale!
Chiggers and lice!
- Looks like they
were pretty hard hit.
- Yeah.
- [Mike] Poor dopes, they
appear every hundred years
and get hit by a huge storm.
- Hi, is there a harbor
master we can talk to?
(speaking foreign language)
- [Tom] Something
about a kinnish?
- Gaelic, huh?
- Didn't sound like
welcome in any language.
- [Crow] So how do you get
your shirt so white, Shamus?
(knocking on door)
- [Mike] Say, quiet man.
- Hey kid, is your
father at home?
- I don't have a father.
- Oh.
Does the harbor
master live here?
- It's the right place
you've come to, then.
Come in.
- [Tom] Did you see me in
"How Green was my Valley?"
- [Crow] Me mum's at
work, so I'm having
a garage sale with her stuff.
- You say the harbor
master lives here?
- Yes, but it's
a city man he is.
A government man.
- Who is he?
What's he do?
- McCartin's his name.
Calls himself an archeologist.
- What's your name?
- Shawn, I work for him.
- Doing what?
- Oh, bits of this
and bits of that.
Cleaning up the things he finds.
- What things?
- You like to see them, then?
- Yeah, sure.
- [Mike] You know, he looks
like a chimp that's dressed up.
(upbeat music)
- [Mike] Hey, look over
there, it's an ancient
Celtic waffle iron.
- [Tom] Cool.
- [Crow] Kid, how
does this huge room
fit into this tiny little hut?
- Well, what do you know?
- [Viewers] Not much, you?
- [Shawn] That's
been under the sea
for a thousand years, they say.
- Viking, looks like.
- Yeah?
- That's it.
It was a great sea battle,
right off bay here.
- [Tom] Great.
- They throwed them off
and sunk their ships.
- What's that?
- [Tom] Oh, that's a taco
gaith bovine growth hormone.
- That's Olgra, the sea spirit.
Just blind like he did that day.
- Sounds like Saint
Patrick and the snakes.
- What are you doing here?
You get out.
- [Mike] Samuel Beckett.
- [Tom] Not cool.
- I'm Joe Ryan.
That's my partner, Sam Slade.
- Hi.
- McCartin's the name.
Salvage vessel, aren't ya?
- Yeah.
- I thought so.
Did the boy tell
you about all this?
- Yeah, a little.
- This stuff has no real value,
except the to our snake head.
But since it turned up,
no ships area allowed
at that island for more than
24 hours without a permit.
- But friend, we're
not sea worthy.
We won't be for
three or four days.
- I don't make the orders,
that's the way it is.
- Anyway, we're afloat.
Come on Sam.
- [Crow] We'll go find
a better harbor master.
- Hey how about fresh water?
- We'll give you that.
- Thanks.
- No hard feelings, now.
- Oh no.
- [Mike] Now wait, you guys
I think there might be.
Please, let's talk this out.
- You believe him,
about this permit?
- No.
- Well, something's eating him.
- [Tom] You mean
besides the lice?
- I wonder what.
- I don't know.
Come on.
Maybe we'll swing a little
more weight around here
if we find out.
- [Crow] But let's get
some boiled cabbage first.
- [Mike] Ah, it's the
yearly silky clubbin'.
- Hey Joe, look.
- [Tom] He's new to sailoring,
he's still pointing out boats.
- Smack her off, Harry.
- [Crow] Beg your pardon?
- [Mike] Oh, we're a
terrible crew team.
- Are you having any luck?
(speaking foreign language)
- You know Joe, they
can talk English
every bit as good
as you and I can.
They just don't
want to, that's all.
- You try, Harry.
(speaking in foreign language)
- He said there's no time
for talking with strangers,
and McCarton does all the
talkin' on the island.
- [Tom] He said, blow it out
your something, I'm not sure.
Joe Strummer goes fishing.
(speaking foreign language)
- Two of the divers
didn't come up, Joe.
They think they're gone.
- Gone?
- [Crow] Yeah, it's a word
meaning not here anymore.
- [Mike] Stop shaking
the boat, I'm gonna puke.
(Servo speaking in
a foreign language)
- There's one.
(speaking foreign language)
- [Crow] He's got two
time release caplets
lets on his back.
- [Tom] Now he's only got one.
- [Mike] Overcome by
an excess of potatoes,
Guinness, and guilt.
- [Tom] Okay, let's take
a look at that butt.
- So that's what's
worrying McCartin.
- [Mike] I should visit
Taneil when I'm ashore.
- [Tom] The mackerel's in the...
- He's dead.
- Dead how?
- [Crow] How dead?
Well, just dead.
- You saw him come up.
You ask me, he died of fright.
- [Tom] Couldn't be the
boiled back fat he ate
everyday of his life.
- [Mike] I think
that's our ship.
It's just they
all look the same.
- This is crazy.
- [Tom] Us marrying.
- There was a man
lost down there today.
Not even a trace.
Another one saw something
that scared him to death.
- Look Sam, you
don't want to go?
Don't go.
- I'm going, all right.
Just to make sure you
get back to shore.
- [Crow] Oh, I got back.
- Sure, with a hat full of gold.
- [Mike] Ha, you get it?
- That's that.
- Yeah, okay.
- [Tom] How do
these things work?
- [Crow] This one
smells like yours.
- [Mike] Boat made of
foot-long hot dogs.
- [Crow] I'm just gonna hang
it out over the side here.
Don't look.
(water splashing)
(suspenseful music)
- [Tom] "Thunder Boar."
- [Crow] "Voyage to the
Bottom of the Yawn."
- [Tom] "The Abysmal."
- [Crow] "Driving Miss Dummy."
- [Mike] Wait, that
doesn't really work at all.
- [Crow] Really?
- [Mike] No, it really fails
on a whole lot of levels.
- [Crow] Well, I
try Mike, all right?
- [Mike] Sorry.
- [Tom] Watch for
sharks, I accidentally
bathed in fish
blood this morning.
Did you say (gurgling)?
- [Crow] Wow, all
this hard water.
Ireland needs the Culligan Man.
- [Mike] Counting
plankton is really hard.
- [Tom] Somebody sunk a
Macy's Thanksgiving Day
parade balloon.
- [Mike] Come on, let's get
some stale bread and feed it.
- [Crow] You know what's
great though, Sam?
I'm wetting my pants in terror,
but it really doesn't
matter down here.
- What did you see, Sam?
- [Tom] Wanna borrow
my old dish towel?
- I don't know.
But whatever it was, I
never wanna see it again.
- [Mike] Oh, like
your this big prize.
♪ Show me the way to go home ♪
♪ Ireland ♪
- [Tom] There's a dead
hobbit in that thing.
- How goes it, Sam?
- These are the last few
barrels coming on board now.
- [Mike] Well clear the stage
for a campy musical review.
- Keep back here, boy.
- Captain wants to see ya.
- [Crow] Thought
his name was McBox.
(speaking foreign language)
- Look kid, get down
off there, will ya?
- A science experiment.
- What about the permit?
- It's heathen lie.
- Maybe we better see what
this joker's got in mind.
Where is he?
- Come on, then.
- Harry.
- [Tom] Well here's the script.
You take my part in
the movie for a while.
- [Mike] Their
Polynesian torch ceremony
isn't too successful this year.
- What's going on here?
- They think a shark
got the man who is lost.
♪ I will call you ♪
- Mister McCartin, I
hear you got a beef.
- You were snoopin'
around out there.
My divers told me.
- Yeah, and I suppose
they told you to give us
all that jazz about a permit.
- Are you doubting my word?
- You're right,
Mr. McCartin, I am.
- [Crow] Look, I'm trying
to write Crap's last tape.
- [Mike] May your corn
beef not pickle correctly.
- After you're loaded
with water, you leave.
Tonight.
- The sooner the better.
- [Tom] The tighter the sweater.
The boys depend on us.
- [Crow] Yay.
There's like one cod left
in the North Atlantic,
but dammit, they're
gonna get it.
(speaking foreign language)
- [Tom] No, it's just
Grandma taking a swim.
Don't!
- [Crow] Oh, ow.
- [Mike] Patty cake, patty cake.
- [Crow] Hey, go
check that out, kid.
- Father.
- [Mike] How are ya?
- [Tom] It's the rare
isosceles underwater dragon.
- [Crow] Really, gentlemen,
must we do this every night?
- [Mike] Oh, poor Robert
Shaw, eaten again.
♪ To reach ♪
(doors creaking and closing)
- Oh hello, I'm Diana Ring.
Inspired by the guy
in today's movie
who looks kind of
like Samuel Beckett,
we present to you a
tragic comedy in one act.
Waiting for Gorgo.
Thank you, won't we?
- Nothing to be done.
- I'm beginning to come
around to that opinion.
- Let's go.
- We can't.
- Why not?
- We're waiting for Gorgo.
- Ah, yes.
(growling and shouting)
- And there he is!
- No no no no.
(clapping and cheering)
- We'll be back
after this message
for whiskey and cigarettes.
(upbeat music)
- [Tom] Oh, that was fun.
- [Crow] Whiskey and cigarettes.
- [Mike] Look at this.
Poor Irish, ya know, if
they're not invaded by Cromwell
or infested with leprechauns,
they got this guy.
- [Tom] I'll get me slingshot.
- Shoot!
(gunshots banging)
♪ Shuffle off to the fellow ♪
- [Mike] McRoar, O'Growl!
(suspenseful music)
- [Tom] Sorry,
I'm a little lost.
Can you tell me how
to get to Tokyo?
- [Mike] Quick, let's emigrate!
- [Tom] This guy's good at
pushing kids around, ya know.
(Gorgo roaring)
- [Mike] Mmm habenero sauce.
- [Crow] Not a very
good juggling act.
- [Mike] A real
shame for the island.
The Let's Go Europe people
are visiting tonight.
- [Tom] These walking
catfish are really big, whew.
- [Crow] Dave Foley.
- [Tom] Come on, I was
just coming to the kallie.
I guess you don't want me, then.
- [Mike] I'll put on my asbestos
underwear and I'll be back!
- [Crow] Fine, I'll
spend my Euros elsewhere.
- [Mike] Well I never.
- [Tom] Open the pub,
come on it's nine a.m.!
- [Crow] We all
hated "End Game."
- Now there's a man looks
like he's got a real problem.
- Uh-huh.
I'll bet he'd pay
through the nose
if we could solve it for him.
- [Mike] I said we're
all out of Lucky Charms.
- Hey, hey, mister.
We'll be wanting a
passage on your ship
just as soon as he gets
around to giving us our pay.
- Now hold on.
You'll get your pay if you like.
But there'll be no taking
a passage on any ship.
- Why not?
(crowd shouting)
- [Crow] I think
they're mumbling a
very good point there.
- Now for god's sake, let's
go inside and talk about it.
- Sure.
- [Tom] He could be a
Baldwin brother, couldn't he?
- If they all leave now,
my portmen, my divers,
the lot of them, then the
whole thing will go to smash.
- Hey, I kinda see their point.
- Got any other reason for
not wanting them to leave?
- What do you mean?
- Oh, like, maybe
they talk to much.
- [Mike] About these
laundry tokens.
- Where did you get those?
- Same place as you.
Supposing we got rid
of that thing for ya.
- The beast?
- [Crow] That's
right, Ian Paisley.
- Do you think you can?
- Maybe.
- [Tom] If you give me one
of your non-sexual massages.
- Let's take another
look in there fast, huh?
- [Mike] I wanna play with
your Hot Wheels again.
- [Tom] Sorry about
how this looks,
the walls need to be re-dunged.
- Open the safe.
- [Crow] Man, I'm
the harbor master.
I don't have to
listen to you guys.
I can go master the
harbor anytime I want.
This is so bogus.
- [Voiceover] You've done
all right for yourself.
- [Tom] Eva.
- How about this
for a down payment?
Do you like this one, Sam?
- You must be out of your mind.
A thing like that is priceless.
- [Mike] It belonged
to Hagar the horrible.
- And how do you think
you're gonna dispose of it?
- You must've figured out a way.
I bet we can.
(shouting indistinctly)
You're getting off easy, friend.
Could've grabbed the lot.
- When will you start?
- Now.
Why not?
- [Mike] Heh, totally toasted
your Irish soda bread.
- Mr. Ryan!
- [Tom] How's your hope?
- [Tom] And your daughter?
- What is it, kid?
- You'll be trying
to catch him, Gorgo.
- Yeah, maybe.
Not afraid, are ya?
- No, but it's a bad
thing you're doing.
A terrible bad thing, Mr. Ryan.
- Why don't you call me Joe?
- Okay, Joe.
- Okay, Shawn.
- [Tom] But you missed my point,
despite our new
familiarity with names.
- Might be able to
catch him in the nets.
- [Crow] Who, the kid?
- Yeah.
- How do you suppose to
kill a thing like that?
- Oh, I don't know.
Dynamite, maybe.
- Ever stop to think
what a thing like that
might be worth alive?
- [Tom] Probably buy a
hundred roll neck sweaters.
- [Mike] Bought it
from the government.
It's called Fatman or something.
- You really think you'll
catch him with that?
- Sure, why not?
I think it'll be a light
selector sort of lure.
If that doesn't work,
we'll try something else.
Okay Harry, come on, okay.
- [Tom] Try something
else, brilliant.
- Johnny, stop!
- [Crow] There's a skeleton of
a little French guy in here.
- Ready when you are, Joe.
- Okay.
Take her up!
- [Tom] Wait wait, what
are you doing to me?
- Take her out, out.
Lower away!
Down!
- [Mike] Cast him over
by those lily pads.
(mysterious music)
- [Crow] Well, I'd sure hate
to go underwater in this thing.
Guys?
- [Tom] He immediately
crossed lines
with the guy trying
to catch Godzilla.
- [Mike] Let's roll
down the window here.
- [Tom] D'oh!
- Tom?
- [Crow] Can I come up now?
- Can you hear me?
- Yeah, I can hear ya.
- Give me about 15 fathoms.
- Down!
- [Tom] Would you let me finish?
- [Mike] Yeah, Civil War
submarine technology.
- [Tom] Why does that
octopus have a hack saw?
- Tom?
- [Crow] I mean it,
I'm really scared now.
- Tom?
- 10 fathoms, how's that?
- Okay, that'll do.
Give me four to five knots.
And try to head down the bay.
- Slow engine!
- [Mike] Shark.
Shark.
- [Tom] A little mood
lighting. (chuckling)
(upbeat music)
- [Crow] Oh, if they don't
let me up to go soon,
it will be a yellow submarine.
(mysterious music)
- [Tom] They drag
him into a rock,
'cause they're so
delighted with the red sky.
- [Mike] Steven Segal.
- Tom, can you hear me?
Stop the engines!
- Stop engines!
- [Crow] Mm, canned guy.
- 10 fathoms, not to fast,
I don't want to lose him.
- Slow up.
Up, up.
- [Tom] What your laundry sees.
- [Mike] Did we
develop a step two yet?
- Tom!
Tom, pull up!
- Up, quick, quick, pull up, up!
- [Crow] Gee,
yeoman pushy pants.
- Tom, Tom, pull up!
- Pull up!
- Arr.
Mm, yummy.
- Tom!
Tom!
Pull up.
- [Mike] Arr.
- Tom, quick!
- Arr!
- Tom, pull out!
- It won't take anymore,
she'll snap the cable!
- Drop the nets!
Drop the nets!
All hands on deck!
(dramatic music)
- [Crow] Hey there's no pop top!
- [Man] Drop it.
- [Man] Drop it!
- [Mike] Now he's
laying his eggs.
He must expect me
to swim over 'em.
- [Crow] So did Gorgo cooperate
and just wrap
himself in the net?
- [Mike] How did this happen?
- [Tom] Dumb.
- [Man] Heavy on the winds!
- [Mike] Light on the starch!
- [Crow] Easy on the mayonnaise!
- [Tom] They're gonna have
a big Gorgo bowl tonight.
- Bring him in!
Lower away!
Tighten up those nets!
- [Mike] Brian just fell
into one of his pores!
- [Crow] Am in Ireland,
send real food.
- [Tom] Hello Mister
and Miss Northumbria
and all the ships at sea.
- The headlines of the entire
world are being monopolized
by the news of the capture
of a fantastic monster,
seemingly of prehistoric origin,
off the coast of Ireland.
Puzzled scientists
are already spectating
that the monster may
have been released
from some vast oceanic cavern,
far beneath the Earth's crust,
by unprecedented
volcanic eruptions
which occurred in
the area last week.
Some scientific
authorities are suggesting
that the whole thing is merely
an elaborate Irish hoax.
Nevertheless, the Irish
government is sending
two of their top paleontologists
to claim the
creature for Ireland.
If it does exist.
- [Crow] Oh they
set up the phone
so he can talk to his family.
- [Mike] Hi honey, got
captured again, yeah.
- There's your
friend, Professor.
- I'll tell my
partner you're here.
Radio, Skipper.
- [Crow] London
turtle neck company
has issued a recall of
potentially fatal flaw.
Oh, great.
- Those two professors from
Dublin just come on board.
- Show 'em up.
- [Tom] I gotta go, honey.
No, I'm fine.
I gotta go, there's some guys.
- I wonder if you
realize, Captain Randy,
the enormous scientific
value of this discovery.
- I think we do, Professor.
- Well then, I shall wire
this to University of Dublin
in order to make preparations
to receive the animal.
You will proceed to Dublin.
- [Mike] Who jiffed?
- Where you'll be properly
compensated for your services.
- Oh, sure, sure.
- Well, we'll meet there.
Unless you would like
one of us to go with you.
- Oh, that won't be
necessary, Professor.
- [Crow] I won't eat much.
- Oh, there's one thing.
The animal's skin
should be kept wet
with a continuous
stream of water.
- I see.
- This is most important.
- I'll take care of it.
- When do you intend
sailing, Captain?
- Tonight, if
that's okay by you.
- Sooner the better.
See you in Dublin.
- University of Dublin.
Properly compensated.
- [Tom] Sentence fragments.
- Big deal.
- Take a look at this, Sam.
- [Tom] Take a
look at this, Sam.
- It's from Jalk
and Sax in London.
They offer 30.000
against 50% of the gross.
- [Crow] 50% of
Mary Gross, I mean.
- Set a course for London, Sam.
- [Tom] I got a
hankerin' for organ meat.
- [Mike] Forgot to
bring in the stringer.
Gorgo's draggin'.
(light music)
- [Crow] Soon Gorgo's
scampering around the deck,
making friends with
all the sailors.
- [Tom] Oh, great.
(ship horn blowing)
- [Mike] Whoa,
that was me, sorry.
(ship horn blowing)
Whoops.
(Tom vocalizing)
- [Crow] Kid, could you salt
yourself and come over here?
- I came to let you
go back to the sea.
- [Crow] Or maybe
lay in some marinade.
- [Mike] I think Gorgo just
needs some new points and plugs.
- [Crow] Go play on Gamra's
back, kid, I'm not into it.
- You little knot head!
What do you think you're doing?!
- Take it easy.
- I came to let him go back
to the sea where he belongs.
- Why?
- Maybe to save your
silly skins for ya.
- I got a good notion to
toss you over the side.
- You wouldn't be
sending me back now.
- Harry.
- Here.
- Better get our little
stowaway into a bunk.
And wash his face.
Harry, put a guard on
that thing 24 hours
and give him a rifle.
- [Crow] Don't give
the monster a rifle.
- I could be watching
him for you, ya know.
Yeah, you, you'd be
great, wouldn't ya?
- Now if it so much as
moves, start shooting,
and then run like the devil.
- [Mike] Pick up my tail
and clatter across the deck
with my cloven hooves?
All right.
- [Tom] Hey, screw,
just reach in my pocket,
get me a cigarette.
- Tell us something, kid.
Anyone ever see
that thing before?
- [Mike] Brandon Bean
did, but he was drunk.
- Why should anybody have to
see it to know it's there?
- [Crow] Is this kid
speaking in Bam-bam language?
- Go back to sleep, kid.
- [Mike] We'll be turning
you over to Interpol.
Good night.
- [Crow] Let's go swipe
the captain's strawberries.
That's always fun, eh?
(ship horn blowing)
♪ Average sized
bubbles in the brine ♪
- Just phosphorus, Sam.
- [Sam] But it's coming
from the scuffers.
- It's the water off the animal.
- So it's still salt water.
- You seeing spirits too?
(man screaming)
- [Tom] Someone didn't rinse
out the sink after he shaved!
- Crew!
The decks, quick!
- [Crow] Gorgo seduced the guard
and then tried to kill him.
- Come on!
- [Tom] I was having an
anti-scurvy lime, but fine.
- [Mike] Oh no, it's
the cute one, d'oh.
- Get him ready for bail, Sam.
Kid, I told you to stay below.
- [Crow] Okay, I'll go
up and stay below, then.
- [Tom] Hot-head.
(upbeat music)
- Filled with butter?
- Guys, look at this.
Guess what I got.
The William Sylvester
version of Trivial Pursuit.
- William Sylvester, hmm?
- Yeah, yeah, I was gonna
get the baby boomer version
of the William Sylvester
version of Trivial Pursuit,
but I just thought the
basic version would be,
you know, a lot more fun.
What color do you want?
- Well, let me answer
that, Mike, by asking you
who the hell is
William Sylvester?
- Come on, he's the
guy in today's movie.
- I'm not recalling any
- Oh come on, he was the
main guy in today's movie.
Plus he was in "Riding with
Death," and "Devil Doll,"
plus "2001: A Space Odyssey,"
plus a whole bunch of other...
Oh, oh, I see what
you guy's are doing.
I see, you're trying to learn
all about William Sylvester
so you can beat me at the
William Sylvester version
of Trivial Pursuit.
Well, it ain't gonna happen!
You can go first though, Crow.
- I don't want to.
- Here you go.
Okay, you have history
of William Sylvester.
Okay, oh, oh man,
this is so easy.
In "2001: A Space
Odyssey," what character
did William Sylvester play?
- I don't know.
- What do you mean you don't?
Haywood Floyd, Haywood Floyd.
Everybody knows that.
- Haywood Floyd.
- Okay, fine, your turn, Servo.
- Oh goody.
Okay, here we go.
- Oh man, this is incredible.
In the movie "Gorgo," who
played the character of Sam?
- I don't know.
- What do you mean?
It was William Sylvester!
It was William, we're
watching the movie today.
Come on, you guys.
You're not even trying.
It's like your
trying to sabotage
my William Sylvester
version of Trivial Pursuit.
- We are, Mike.
- We patently don't care
about William Sylvester.
- Not a bit.
- So you're conceding.
- Yes, we concede.
- Yes! Yes! Yes! Yes!
I know more about William
Sylvester than you do.
Or you.
Yes, yes!
(alarm blaring)
- Sad, really.
- Woo hoo hoo, oh movie time!
(doors creaking and thudding)
- [Mike] Yes, yes.
- [Tom] Your own game.
- [Mike] Whew.
- [Tom] And Buddy
Hackett on trumpet.
- Down.
Down.
Let her clear.
Keep her clear.
- [Crow] Men not without hats.
- [Man] All right,
lower it a bit.
- Unique in
evolutionary biology,
and you turn it
into a circus freak.
Outrageous.
Quite apart from the
fact that you stole it.
- [Mike] Dorkin.
- Now that's a
matter of opinion.
- What's this all about?
- We know absolutely
nothing about this animal.
It's extremely dangerous.
- We've managed to handle
it all right so far.
- [Tom] One guy died, but.
- They carry disease-bearing
parasites or unknown bacteria.
- [Crow] Like me.
- And you bring it into
the heart of a great city.
- Look, what do you want?
- First the opportunity
to make a complete study.
- Okay.
If it doesn't interfere
with business.
- Believe me, gentlemen, once
the animal is been stored
in Battersea Park, you'll
be given every facility.
- I presume you've thought of
the need of giving the animal
a tranquilizing drug
before you transport it?
'Cause if you
haven't, you'd better.
- Well, they bet on it.
- Good day.
- [Tom] Which one of
these guys is Dorkin?
It's hard to tell
from this picture.
- [Mike] Yes, Dorkin
means great entertainment.
- [Crow] Dorkin
under the big top.
Come see the delightful
Dorkin midgets
and the funny Dorkin clowns.
- [reporter] In our most
unusual telecast to date,
we bring you the
arrival of Gorgo.
This creature, which
should of been extinct
10 million years ago, is
truly an awesome sight
as it is transported though
the streets of modern London
on it's way to Battersea Park.
Of course, Londoners are
notoriously skeptical.
And a good many
we've spoken too...
(viewers muttering loudly)
But this animal is real.
Take my word for it.
- [Mike] I'm Dennis Thatcher.
- [Reporter] The
police have cleared all
unauthorized traffic
along the route,
as a precautionary measure.
Although we're assured
there's no danger,
the creature has been given
massive doses of tranquilizer.
Much closer to this
thing, and I could do
with a bit of
tranquilizer myself.
Actually, it's no joke.
- [Crow] I need drugs.
- [Reporter] There are
rumors that the animal
has killed a number
of persons already
in the process of its capture.
- [Tom] But they were
all Irish, so it's okay.
- [Reporter] Now we can
see the circus crowds
at Battersea Park in
the festival gardens,
where Gorgo, as he is
called, we don't know why,
will be exhibited to the public.
- [Mike] And Hitler pulls up.
- Here we can see the
intrepid Captain Ryan,
the one with the cap,
getting out of the car
with his partner, Mr. Slade.
- [Crow] Flintstone!
- Here's the man who
captured the animal.
And I don't envy them the job.
And our own Mr. Dorkin,
of Dorkin's Circus,
in the checkered suit.
- [Crow] In the chicken suit?
- [Reporter] And by the way-
- [Mike] That I don't see.
- [Voiceover] Shortly at
Battersea Park, so stay with us.
And of course, ladies and
gentlemen, I realized at once
that this was the most
shattering scientific discovery
of the 20th century,
and so I contracted
for the exhibition
of the animal.
We've built a special enclosure,
you'll see it later on.
We rushed the job through,
just so everyone in London
would have an opportunity of
seeing Gorgo for themselves.
- I have a report from Dublin
that the Irish government
are going to take
legal proceedings to
recover the animal.
- Yes, I believe
that to be true.
Of course, the matter
will have to go through
the courts in the usual way.
And since I have no way
of knowing how quickly
they'll reach their
decision, I suggest
that anyone who
wants to see Gorgo
does so soon at Battersea Park.
- That name, Gorgo.
Does it have any
special significance?
- Yes sir, of course, the
monster of Greek mythology.
The Gorgons.
A creature so terrifying
that the mere sight of it
would turn a man to stone.
- [Mike] This is for Dorkin.
- How much money do you
expect to make out of it?
- I'll answer that
question later on.
- [Crow] Don't bother
the man, he's Dorkin.
- [Tom] Oh, they
have to clean up
after Mighty Joe Young first.
- Lower away.
- Lower away!
Easy!
- Okay, Tom.
- Easy does it!
- [Crow] One day at a time.
Be in the moment.
Don't sweat the small stuff.
- [Tom] The net's
digging into my groin,
if you could just...
- [Man] Fore!
- [Mike] Playing through.
- Tranquilizer
seems to be working.
- [Crow] I'm very mellow.
- So far.
- [Tom] Is there a union
for monster wranglers here?
- [Mike] Wanna help, Joe?
- [Crow] They're trying to
exhume William Howard Taft.
- [Man] Wire cutters.
- Wire cutters, quick.
- Okay.
- Cut the net, boys.
- [Tom] He has a splinter,
let's take care of that first.
- [Mike] Mm, world's
biggest porchetta.
- [Crow] Look we all know
where this is heading.
Can we just start
tossing Brits around?
- [Tom] Mr. Gorgo, is it
true you had an affair
with Judith Asner?
- That's a hell of
a dumb thing to do.
- [Tom] I'm up, I'm up.
- [Crow] Yeah,
I've got net hair.
(Gorgo roaring)
♪ I crush you ♪
♪ You get crushed ♪
- [Mike] This is like
England's 178th finest hour.
- [Tom] Help us, help!
- [Mike] The Japanese that
lies dormant in all of us
comes to the surface in
situations like these.
- [Tom] Mm-hmm.
Oops.
- Over here!
- [Crow] Sit.
You sit.
- [Mike] Hey, best
teeth in England.
- [Tom] Free Huey.
(shouting indistinctly)
- [Crow] This is truly a black
day in the history of Dorkin.
- [Mike] Will this
stop England's Dorkin?
- [Tom] He looks like
a chocolate bunny.
- [Mike] Aw, looks like Crow.
- [Crow] Ooh, I didn't know
elephants exploded on impact.
- [Tom] Wow.
- Come on, this way.
- We'll take the other side.
- [Mike] We've
installed this system
rather than the traditional
hand towels, Gorgo.
It prevents chapping
and spread of disease.
(Gorgo roaring)
- [Tom] I left
instructions with Mothra.
If I don't come back, he's
gonna wreck this joint!
- Give him another blast!
- [Crow] Embarass him!
Ask him about the
size of his brain!
- [Mike] Look, can I
just eat Manchester?
- [Crow] Oh, right in the store.
- Wow.
- [Mike] Quit draggin'
tail, Gorgo, come on.
Poor guy was just there for
take your brother to work day.
- [Tom] Gorgo gave
himself a little time out.
- [Crow] Buses really run
frequently here in London.
- [Mike] Come see Gorgo,
he'll kill your family.
Come get killed by Gorgo.
- [Crow] Dorkin with
John Collins' big dipper.
Happy couples enjoying
Dorkin all night long.
(cheerful music)
- [Mike] Hey, it is balloons.
Insulation on a stick.
- [Reporter] Everybody in the
world is talking about Gorgo,
but only you can see him,
and only here at Dorkins.
Two lanes, both sides, five
shillings, ladies and gentlemen.
Bring the children,
very instructive.
This way.
Hurry, hurry,
hurry to see Gorgo.
The last remaining link
with prehistoric times.
Only five shillings,
ladies and gentlemen.
- [Crow] Hooray for Dorkin!
- There a still a
few remaining places.
Two lanes, both sides.
Bring the children,
very instructive.
What's that, madam,
looks like your husband?
Go inside to find out.
65-foot high Gorgo, and
heavier than six elephants.
- [Tom] Oh, that this
too too solid flesh
would melt, thaw, and
resolve itself into a dew.
- [Crow] It's reject
day at the circus.
- [Man] Ice cream here,
get your ice cream.
♪ Mr. Bojangles ♪
- Peanuts, popcorn!
- [Tom] Hey, John Quincy Adams.
- Get your peanuts here.
(Gorgo roaring)
♪ It's not unusual ♪
- [Crow] Thank you.
(crowd chattering)
- [Mike] Mm, brain matter.
- [Tom] Hi there,
cutie, heh heh.
- [Crow] Hey ladies,
I know Gorgo.
Wanna meet him?
- Looks like a full house.
- Not bad.
- [Mike] That's why I'm Dorkin.
♪ Don't break my heart,
my achy breaky heart ♪
- [Crow] Great, Colonel Tom
Parker's gonna manage Gorgo.
- [Tom] Next show in
half an hour, Mr. Gorgo.
- Hi, Sam.
I was driving into town.
Thought you might like to come
along, have a couple drinks.
- I'm having a couple of drinks.
- [Tom] I'm just tearing
through the pink squirrels.
- How's business?
- [Sam] Great, great.
- Why don't you get
out of this dump?
Live a little.
I got a suite of rooms at
the best hotel in town.
- [Crow] Gorgo's got
the big bed, but.
- This suits us.
(elephant screeching)
- [Mike] Great, Gorgo
ate another elephant.
- Look Joe, these
animals are gone crazy.
Something's gonna
happen, I can feel it.
Mike's already been killed.
Who's gonna be next?
- I'm as sorry about
Mike as you are.
It's a tough break, that's all.
- Well, he's got a
wife and two kids.
- Okay, well we'll
send her some money.
- But he's dead.
- [Tom] Okay, we'll send
her another husband.
- There's gonna be a
lot more tough breaks
before this is over.
- You've been listening to
your new partner too much.
- I've been listening to myself.
(phone ringing)
- [Crow] Oh,
that'll be me again.
- Hello.
(Tom growls)
Yeah, just a moment.
It's the professor.
Says they've been
trying to find ya.
- [Tom] Do you
know where you are?
- This time of night?
Hello?
Yeah.
- [Crow] I'm
smoking, sure, yeah.
- Yeah if you say so.
Okay.
- [Mike] Well, I'm
suppose to hit you.
- Spotted something
out, you coming along?
- Yeah, sure.
- [Crow] Then we'll go
beat up some clowns.
(cheerful music)
- [Tom] But I don't want
to be Billy and mummy.
- [Mike] I hope Moneypenny's
happy to see me.
- [Crow] Holy worm's
busiest day ever.
- Come in gentlemen.
Captain Ryan.
- [Tom] Yes.
- The creature you captured
is not an adult specimen.
- You mean it isn't fully grown?
- No.
In fact, we believe it is
in rather early infancy.
- [Tom] You'll
need to change him.
- You trying to say there
may be a fully grown
one of these things
around somewhere?
- It's a fair assumption.
Where there are offspring,
there are generally parents.
- How big would a
full-grown one be?
- Approximate guess.
- [Mike] According to my
unnecessarily large book.
- [Professor] The infant.
- [Crow] The out-fant.
- [Professor] The adult.
- That would make him
nearly 200 feet tall.
- At the very least.
- Obviously the proper
authorities must be
notified at once.
- What are you trying to do?
Stir up a whole hornet's nest?
Because of a few calculations
made on a piece of paper?
Nuts to that.
- I'm afraid, Captain
Ryan, the decision
is no longer in your hands.
- [Tom] One, two, three, step.
Two, no wrong.
Practice, practice, practice.
Two, three.
- [Mike] Boy, these late
shows, nobody ever comes.
- [Crow] Hey kid,
wanna play me eat you?
- [Tom] What's that?
Oh, pain! (shouting)
What did I just experience?
Oh yeah, pain! (shouting)
(dog howling)
- [Mike] Ooh, he's got
Betty Davis eye, real bad.
- [Crow] Yikes.
- [Tom] I held my breath for
a million years, did you see?
- [Mike] Quiet, I'm
finishing a monologue
for Billy Whitelaw.
- [Crow] Ow, I stubbed
my toe on a duplex.
- [Tom] It's the road
company of Stomp.
- [Mike] I'm the
new harbor master.
(suspenseful music)
- [Tom] Ah, this feels great.
Oh, my achin' dogs.
- Admiral Brooks, I realize
the situation is fantastic.
- One expects the fantastic
from your scientists these days.
- [Mike] Stupid squid.
- Tell me Admiral,
have you ever seen
the animal that was captured?
- I'm afraid I
haven't had the time.
- Then perhaps you
should take the time.
And when you do, remember it
first appeared at Nada Island.
- Monitor reports there's
been no communication
with Nada Island
for three days, sir.
- [Tom] Thank you, Timmy.
- Three days?
- [Crow] Oh, and Pinafore's
about to start, sir.
- Her majesty's air craft
carrier, Royal Open.
From the Admiral T. Whitehall.
Proceed to area N34, and
report any unusual sightings
or conditions in
vicinity of Nada Island.
This is priority A.
Repeat.
♪ One ♪
- [Crow] Meanwhile,
bits of the empire
are falling away, so long,
India, goodbye, Rhodesia.
- [Mike] Talmud,
Talmud, oh wait.
I mean, Torah, Torah.
(Tom murmuring)
- [Crow] Leave me
alone, get away from me.
- [Mike] The SS
Curly has arrived.
(imitating Three Stooges)
- [Crow] Hmm, there's
a spot on my window.
- [Mike] I'm drawing Binky.
- Reconnaissance to corvette.
Alter course to three-one-zero.
Repeat, course three-one-zero.
(alarm blaring)
- [Tomorrow] Soytenly. Nyuk,
nyuk, nyuk, nyuk, nyuk.
- Right.
They spotted something, sir.
- Port four points.
- Port, four points.
- Aye-aye.
- [Crow] Going
over our own wake.
It's fun.
- [Mike] Deploy
pitching machine.
- [Tom] The order comes in.
Kill Willy.
- [Crow] She has perm
rods in her hair.
- [Mike] Man, I love krill.
- Fire number one turret.
(turrets booming)
- [Tom] Wait wait, we can't
all be number one turret.
- [Crow] Whoa.
- [Mike] Look at this,
doormen just roam
the streets of London
looking for people to serve.
(telegraphs beeping)
- [Tom] I will not
fake distress calls.
I will not fake distress calls.
- Admiral Brooks.
- [Crow] We decided
England is shaped funny.
- Gentlemen, you've
been asked to come here
to supply us with any
information in your position
which might be helpful.
Nada Island has been destroyed.
Reconnaissance aircraft
has sighted the creature
in this area here.
- If you ask me, sir,
that looks as though
the thing's heading for England.
- Quite.
Her majesty herself
called for an explanation.
Do you have one?
- Well, we were draining
a stream of water on it
during the passage.
It was Professor
Flahherty's instructions.
Maybe he left some
sort of track.
- I see.
- [Mike] Way to go.
- Is that possible?
- Yes, it's possible.
- The Royal Oak for
Admiral Brooks, please.
Royal Oak coming in
for Admiral Brooks.
- Good.
- [Crow] My charcoal is here.
- They report at
least two direct hits.
- You killed it?
- It's disappeared
beneath the sea.
They saturated the area
with death charges.
No living thing could escape.
It's certainly been killed.
- [Tom] We killed it, Moe.
(dramatic music)
- [Mike] A giant sea camel.
- [Tom] Ah, pork-fed grits.
- [Mike] There's got to
be a morning after, sir.
- Capsized?
- [Crow] I've got to
have my cap sized.
- With every man aboard.
- This is terrible.
- [Mike] I see it
as an opportunity.
- Well, all right, now what?
- What will you do?
- Turn that thing at
the festival gardens
loose, what else?
Take it back to the sea,
while we still got the chance.
- What the hell's
a matter with you?
This is the 20th century.
There must be someway of
handling an over-grown animal.
- There's no doubt that
we can stop the creature.
- [Tom] Yes.
- We'll call you if
we need you again.
Good evening gentlemen.
- [Crow] Ah but could
you postpone your plans
to bring the
500-foot stick insect
into the middle of London?
(upbeat music)
- [Tom] Dorkin just
doesn't seem that same now.
- [Mike] Nope.
Good night Gorgo.
- Roar.
- [Tom] The clowns let
me borrow their car.
It's great!
- [Mike] Well, I do
live in a trailer.
Better listen to some Bob
Seger and watch Nascar.
- Sam, stop, he'll kill you.
- I'm turning him loose.
- Stop it, Sam!
He'll kill you!
- Only chance.
Let him go!
- [Crow] Don't
vomit on me again.
(Gorgo roaring)
- [Tom] Don't fuss
so over me, please.
- [Mike] Fem-punch.
(Gorgo roaring)
- Stop it Sam, you're crazy.
- [Crow] Hmm, I
like punching you.
- [Tom] We're going
to the vet, right?
- Sam!
Are you all right? Sam.
Are you all right?
Sam.
- [Tom] You made
the pants too long.
- Sam.
- Go on, kid.
♪ Fail, Britainia ♪
♪ You never ruled the waves ♪
(turret booming)
- [Mike] Ah, here.
- [Crow] Well, we've
taken out the QE2,
the Bismark, and the Loveboat,
but we've missed Gorgo.
- [Tom] Oh, look what
the neighbors are doing.
- Reconnaissance to corvette.
Observation negative.
Repeat, negative.
- [Mike] Can I get
some help here?
There's usually a
guy with a thing.
- Fire with all hands,
the admiralty has deployed
major forces of the NATO fleet
off the mouth of the estuary
in an attempt to locate
and destroy the monster
even before it reaches
the coastal defenses.
- [Crow] They're
firing geese at him.
(dramatic music)
- [Mike] L, L, L.
L, L, L.
- [Crow] R R R, R R R R.
- [Tom] They must
get everything.
- Still tracking west 25.
- Roger task force.
Search 20 degrees west.
- [Mike] Ma!
- [Crow] Oh, he's so cute.
- [Tom] Is Roger looking at me?
- [Mike] Look at those
two, it's disgusting.
(dramatic music)
- [Crow] You know at this point,
I'd be glad to see Cher
straddling these guns.
- [Tom] Isn't this cutting into
the navy's groping
and harassment time?
- [Mike] The English reject
beer that's too cold.
(explosions booming)
- [Crow] This is the
equivalent of the Navy
getting drunk and throwing
cherry bombs over board.
- [Tom] 10 whales are dead, sir.
(dramatic music)
- [Mike] We are a
submarine, right?
Good.
- [Crow] Ooh, ooh, I think
I just saw Larry Hovas.
- [Mike] Where?
- [Man] That's the cue, sir.
- [Tom] Oops, we left the
captain in the accounting tower.
- Steady as she goes
for torpedo check.
Course two-seven-five,
range 1500.
- [Man] Course
two-seven-five, sir.
Firing check.
- Ready to open fire, sir.
- Tile one.
- [Mike] Movie much longer
than it would've been
without us, sir.
- Fire two.
- [Crow] Can't talk now, bye.
- Attacking target
in search area.
- [Tom] I need a bigger monitor.
- Contact broken.
Target moving
toward the estuary.
Too fast to follow.
- Getting submarine control.
Sector two-eight.
- We're just closing the
last of the submarine nets
now, sir.
- Mm-hmm.
- Yes, sir.
- [Mike] This must keep
foul balls out of the ocean.
- [Tom] Cigarette alert.
Everybody smoke.
(alarm blaring)
- Yes?
Yes!
Oh no, the nets have been torn,
and the connection is gone.
- [Crow] Just got red contacts.
What do ya think?
(dramatic music)
- Nice.
- [Mike] Wow, lieutenant modest
crotch on the right here.
- Nothing further
you can do now.
- [Tom] Well, they've
forgotten your Moo Goo Gai Pan.
- The creatures got through.
Smashed the nets.
- Get me river patrol.
(dramatic music)
- [Tom] Uh-oh.
- [Crow] Hey hey
hey, it's Fat Albert.
- [Mike] Now is this
the mom or the dad?
- [Tom] I don't know.
How do you sex one
of these things?
- [Crow] Well, you put
the lights down low,
you put on a little Barry White.
- [Tom] That's not what I mean.
That's ridiculous.
(speaking foreign language)
- [Mike] Let's get outta here.
- [Man] You can see the
huge beast still advancing.
Second line of defense
has been organized,
greatly reinforced.
(doors creaking and closing)
- Oh hey, what's this?
- Looks like the nanites made
them self a little circus.
- Oh, they must've been
watching the movie,
the little dickenses.
- Well, let's see.
Hello nanites, what's
going on down there?
(cheerful music)
- [Tom] Ladies and gentlemen!
Children of all ages!
Come to the
spectacular, gargantuan,
nanite protos and
darkened combined,
avionic circus and
carnival of souls.
- [Crow] With Nate the clown.
- [Tom] Marvel at the spectacle
of wild subcelluar animals.
- [Crow] With Nate the Clown.
- [Tom] Thrill at the daring
of the Nanitino family
as they fly a full 15
mic-grounds about center ring.
- [Crow] And Nate the Clown.
- Whoa, it sounds great.
How much does it cost?
- [Tom] I'm not done yet.
Gasp in horror at the
largely ironic midway
and squeal with delight at
the antics of Nate the Clown.
- [Crow] Hey, that's
me. (laughing)
- Okay, okay, you sold me.
How much?
- [Tom] Only 25 cents!
That's right, a quarter.
Two bits, five nickels,
one quarter of a greenback.
- Well, I've got a
handful of quarters.
You guys in?
- You bet.
- I want to see
the ironic midway.
- Here you go, pallie.
(Tom shouts)
- [Tom] Oh horrors, the curse
of the circus is upon us.
Giant stones fall from the
sky, and our clown is dead.
- [Crow] Ah, the microbes
are on the loose.
The ameobas are on the rampage.
Run!
(Tom shouting)
- Ow, sorry.
I was just tossing one on.
- [Tom] Here comes another.
The circus is destroyed!
- Maybe we should go
to the zoo instead.
- That's a good idea.
We'll be right back.
- Clown killer.
- Maybe.
(upbeat music)
- [Crow] Geez, did ya
see that clown blood?
- [Mike] Whoopsy.
- [Tom] I don't think the
sanctions are working.
- Get your lines ready, sir.
- Open the valves.
- [Crow] Ah, they're gonna get
it drunk on woodpecker cider.
♪ Downtown ♪
- [Man] Come on, hop to it.
- [Tom] McHale's Navy
valiantly battles the creature.
(Gorgo roaring)
- [Crow] Come on,
it's the 5:15 monster.
- Be ready.
Let's get behind those sandbags.
- [Mike] This feels
good, squishing the
mud between my toes.
- Fire!
(gunshot bangs)
- [Tom] Got him.
He's dead, it's over, let's go.
- [Mike] Good, let's go.
- [Crow] This is a fine welcome.
They treated Jerry Lee
Lewis better than this.
- [Mike] Bollocks, Gorgo.
- [Crow] Now that just
seemed completely avoidable.
- Get me army headquarters.
- Atomic weapons are out
of the question. (mumbling)
- [Tom] Wacko!
- Tanks? Of course.
- [Man] Move out, move out!
Up you go.
- [Mike] Come on, let's
do something easy,
like put down some
Arabs or something.
- [Tom] These things are great.
They're built like Volvos.
- Attention.
This is a special bulletin.
Civil defense
authorities have declared
a state of emergency
for all London areas
within three miles
of the River Thames.
- [Crow] Ah, he'll
probably be sated on people
from the suburbs by then.
- [Tom] There's a
sale on bumber shoots.
(man mumbling)
- [Crow] See, not so bad.
Keep your chin up.
Stiff upper lip.
- [Man] The streets
must be kept clear
for military and
defense personnel.
- [Mike] And Good Humor trucks.
- [Tom] Ah, the queen mum is
brought out to fight the beast.
Hello.
(shouting indistinctly)
- [Tom] Yes, sir.
- [Crow] Being in the
British army is a cinch.
You just hold a rifle,
run around, and look busy.
- Come on.
- [Man] Get off the streets.
- [Crow] Okay.
- [Mike] No, no he's
talking to guys.
- [Man] You will be notified
when the emergency is over.
Get off the streets
and go to your homes.
- [Mike] Now tanks are brought
in to roll over the doll.
- [Crow] Yeah, this is
the same thing they do
when Oliver Reid's in town.
- [Tom] Can't believe
we all missed the bus.
- [Man] Up the ramp there.
Move in, move in.
Take your positions.
Parting positions!
- It's advancing up river
directly towards us.
- [Crow] Stay here
and get killed?
Yes sir.
- Very good, sir.
- [Tom] A woman.
- Although the army
indicates full confidence,
they report growing
casualties among their forces.
We are told that Downing Street
is in constant communication
with other world capitals, but
grave concern is expressed.
- [Mike] Though I detected
a snicker in their voice.
(whistle blows)
- Call headquarters.
Shoot the flares!
(gunshot bangs)
Open side fire!
Standby!
Commence fire!
- [Crow] Hey, wait,
I don't have my gun!
Oh, I see.
(gunshots banging)
- [Mike] You're the ones who
sold me my anti-missile armor.
- [Crow] Ah this is really
cleaning my pores, thank you.
- [Tom] Now Mike,
you're probably gripped
with the urge to say London
Bridge is falling down
at this point, but don't, don't!
This is actually
the Tower Bridge.
♪ London Bridge
is falling down ♪
- [Tom] Mike, what
did I just tell you?
- [Mike] What?
Oh, right, sorry.
(Gorgo roaring)
(Crow shouts)
- [Mike] Why, that's
quite bracing,
getting knocked off the bridge.
- [Tom] Ooh, red ants!
- The bridge is gone!
One of London's oldest
landmarks, smashed
like matchwood.
Nothing can stop this
beast so far, nothing.
Not even point blank canon fire.
- [Tom] Not women.
- The entire bridge?
Then the power of this
thing is fantastic.
- [Tom] And I'm on
half power as it is!
(Gorgo roaring)
- [Crow] Hi, I'm Gorgo,
but I'm not Mormo
of the thousand-faced moon.
- [Tom] Maybe Mary Poppins
flies in and kicks his ass.
- [Mike] That I'd pay to see.
No, he has the power
to superimpose rocks.
- Check the missile units.
- Yes sir.
- [Crow] Cliff Richards is
opening up the palladium.
- [Tom] Juggling
pins I brought in,
and the monster is
challenged to keep
five up in the air at once.
- Meanwhile, the Russians
slip in the back door,
take over London, and
rename it Khrushchevgrad.
- [Crow] They could fling
really hot curry in his eyes.
- [Tom] Yeah, or spray
him with malt vinegar.
- Back, back, come back!
- Yes sir, I will.
40 degrees!
- [Crow] Hey, it's Large Bob.
- [Mike] It's Big Ben.
- [Crow] Oh sure, Mike.
(Gorgo roaring)
- [Tom] Think it's noticeable?
- [Mike] Nah.
- [Tom] Oh boy.
- [Crow] Big Ben.
- [Mike] Ah, it was running
a little fast anyway.
(dramatic music)
- [Crow] Got a few people
caught in my teeth.
(Gorgo screeching)
- Come on.
- [Tom] I want access
to the Law Library.
- Burned out our connection.
- [Mike] Here, let's
check is air pressure.
Maybe that's the problem.
- Where's Shawn?
- [Crow] Ah, General Shawn.
Glad we found you.
- Shawn!
Come on.
- [Tom] Come on, we have to
rescue our child that we hate.
- All homes in this area
must be evacuated at once.
- [Mike] The Darlings.
- You have no time to
remove your belongings.
Get out of the area.
Proceed in a westerly direction.
- [Crow] Well, the good
news is he may crush Sting.
- [Tom] You think so?
- [Crow] Could be.
- [Mike] Good news for everyone.
- [Tom] A lot of people
will end up in hospital
because of this, perhaps
even people from university.
(Mike vocalizing)
- [Crow] Oh, not her majesty's
certified paper clip works,
purveyors of paper clip to her
majesty's court since 1743.
(car horn honking)
- [Tom] It's the London
landmark Banco Espanol.
- [Mike] Hang on, I
gotta change some pesos.
- [Crow] It's a Lulu
autograph session.
- Run that way, Sam.
We'll meet back at Battersea!
- [Mike] Great, about four?
I'll bring some beer.
(people screaming)
- [Tom] What, what,
am I offending?
- [Mike] Maybe he just
hates Georgian architecture.
- [Tom] Maybe.
- [Crow] Oof, I hope
that's not a mating call.
- [Tom] I'm glad you're
killing Mother, Gorgo.
- [Mike] You need
to find Elton John
so he can write a
song about this.
♪ Goodbye England ♪
♪ You've been crushed
by giant lizards ♪
- [Crow] Big Ben.
- [Mike] Hey, I'm just looking
for a good hat blocker.
(upbeat music)
(car horn honking)
I assume King Edward has
sold of all England's secrets
to Gorgo by now.
- [Tom] Man, you are tub, kid.
- [Crow] I won't marry you.
- [Mike] Yes you will.
(people screaming)
- [Tom] Come on, my car's
gonna get towed, move!
- [Mike] At this point,
he's using the kid
as a battering ram.
- [Tom] You know, if it were me,
I'd just hang back and
kinda look inconspicuous.
- [Crow] Yeah,
duck into a corner,
pull my hat down,
read the paper.
- [Mike] Aren't you
glad you used Dial?
- [Tom] This guy panicked
but he stopped the path.
♪ I'm looking over
a four leaf clover ♪
- [Crow] Stubby Kaye,
Al Lewis, Archie Rice.
- [Tom] Ooh, scabby knees.
(people screaming)
- [Mike] I trust event figure
will get me through this.
- [Tom] Insti-flood.
- It's all right, Shawn.
We'll be all right.
- [Crow] It's Gorgo sweat.
- [Mike] Hey look, I
don't want to be near you.
Take me back to the soldiers.
- [Tom] By the way, does
this mean no work tomorrow?
(car horn honking)
- [Crow] Oh man, I floated
an air biscuit back there.
I gotta get away from it.
- Piccadilly, the
heart of London.
Words can't describe it.
- [Mike] I'll speak
in whole numbers.
- Not even the
worst of the Blitz.
This section is
complete shambles.
People running mad with fear.
Fires everywhere.
- [Tom] The fire department
still running over people.
- [Crow] Hello, Piccadilly.
First I'm gonna see a Noel
Coward play on the west end.
- [Mike] I'm so proud.
My son's name in lights.
- [Tom] What should I
do with this building?
I'll crush it I guess.
It's what I do best.
There, yeah.
- [Mike] People are running
through the streets saying,
"this simply isn't done.
You'll be hearing
from my solicitor."
- [Tom] He's everywhere.
- I can't see anything now.
There's too much smoke.
- [Crow] Hey kid, give
that guy in a wheelchair
a little kick, he's in our way.
(Gorgo roaring)
- Piccadilly Circus?
There's no way of telling where
this thing will turn next.
(people screaming)
I don't care how important
it is, you must interrupt.
It's imperative that I speak
to the Minister at once.
- [Tom] But the Minister
nipped out to bingo.
(dramatic music)
- [Mike] And they sneak
off and bomb the Falklands.
- [Tom] I wish they'd
get back to Dorkin.
- [Crow] Yeah, there
was a lot of Dorkin
at the beginning of the movie.
They should show that some more.
- [Tom] Sure, I mean who
wouldn't rather watch Dorkin
than this stock footage.
- [Crow] I just really, really
like to watch people Dorkin.
- [Mike] Hey, that
doesn't even work.
- [Crow] Oh, it works,
Mike. (chuckling)
- [Mike] That's enough, you two.
Enough Dorkin.
You know what I mean, stop it.
- [Tom] Zinga.
Maybe they could drop
Robbie Coltrane on them.
- [Mike] Yeah, or how
about the two fat ladies?
- [Tom] Pacifist or
not, Ghandi's gotta be
chuckling about now.
- [Crow] Oh, let me guess.
The air force is ineffectual.
- [Mike] Bring it on,
it's like eating pad thai.
- Repent!
Repent!
- [Tom] Oh no,
it's well past tea.
(man shouting indistinctly)
- Repent!
Repent.
- [Crow] I'm not
wearing any pants!
No pants, baby!
- [Tom] Mike, can one repent
if one hasn't yet pented?
- [Mike] I'll get back to you.
- [Tom] Okay.
- I see.
Well, let me know
the moment you are.
- [Mike] You needed
a vaudeville team?
- Thanks for coming.
- It's undoubtedly heading
for Battersea Park, sir.
That's the place to stop it.
- How much voltage do you
estimate will be required
for electrocuting this animal?
- Two million,
three million volts?
Just a guess.
There's not much
precedent to go on that.
- Get me Battersea
Power Station.
- [Tom] You brought
the wrong kid.
- Is he okay?
- [Crow] Say hello to
the nice folks, Bobby.
- He'll be all right.
- [Mike] I use turtle
wax to prevent chipping.
- [Tom] Toenail fungus, yikes.
- Switch on.
Full power.
- [Crow] Ah, they got the
new Pudding Master 5000.
♪ If I ruled the world ♪
♪ Every day would be the
first day of spring ♪
- [Mike] Okay, drop it.
(suspenseful music)
- [Crow] Man, these little
army guys are chewy.
- [Tom] Director
had a foot fetish.
- We're waiting at Battersea.
Waiting.
- [Mike] Would you die?
- Praying for a miracle.
The entire electricity
of all industrial London
has been diverted to
the wires surrounding
the small animals enclosure.
Will it be enough?
Will it be enough to
stop the huge beast?
Will the miracle be granted?
Or will it be yet another
of man's puny efforts
to oppose this irresistible
force of ancient nature?
- [Mike] After this
message from Cat Brain.
- Hey, Sam. (mumbling)
- [Tom] You're wearing
the tie I bought you.
- [Crow] How the hell
do you work this thing?
- [Mike] My shield's almost
down, hull breech eminent.
- [Tom] He's heading
for the hot tub.
- [Crow] I'm rather
put out by all this.
- [Mike] Quit readjusting
the subwoofer.
- The power circuit has
just been completed, sir.
(Gorgo roaring)
- What's the reading?
- Four million volts
and full amperage, sir.
The lines won't take anymore.
- [Crow] Give me back my son.
- [Mike] I love you, Mimsy.
- [Tom] Oh, big amperage?
- [Crow] Mom, you're
embarrassing me.
(Tom vocalizing)
- [Mike] Our cast,
in case you forgot.
- [Tom] Dorkin.
Sorry.
(Gorgo screeching)
- She's going down.
No, now she's torn the wires.
Now, nothing!
- [Mike] I think the editing
philosophy of this movie
was don't stay on
anything too long.
It doesn't look good enough.
- [Crow] This is treating
my bipolar disorder.
(Tom laughing)
- [Tom] You're coming
with me, young lizard.
Aww.
- [Crow] Damn Mom, you're big.
- [Mike] Kiss my tail, England.
- We prayed for a miracle.
- [Tom] Now to cricket scores.
- Maybe our prayers
have been answered.
The great city,
overwhelmed, exhausted,
lies helpless under
the immeasurable power
and ferocity of this
towering apparition
from before the dawn of history.
- [Crow] Why didn't
she eat the announcer?
- [Reporter] Yet, as though
disdaining the pygmies
under our feet, she turns back.
- [Mike] Yeah, that's me.
- [Reporter] Turns
with her young,
leaving the prostrate city.
Leaving the haunts of man,
and leaving man himself
to ponder the proud
boast that he alone
is lord of all creation.
- [Tom] Shut up!
Windbag.
- [Crow] So Mom, how's Dad?
- [Mike] I ate him.
- [Crow] Oh.
- They're going back
now, back to the sea.
- [Tom] With the blood
of many on her scales.
(dramatic music)
- [Mike] Come on, son.
As a treat, let's
go crush France.
- [Tom] Hurray!
- [Crow] Now the
rest of the story
is the Cray brothers
looting London.
- [Tom] This is how
"My Giant" ends.
(viewers humming)
- [Crow] Oh, Dorkin was
a person, a character.
Weird.
- [Tom] First naval officer?
There weren't any naval
officers before this movie?
- [Mike] I don't think he was
the first naval officer ever.
- [Tom] No, that's precisely
what they're saying.
- [Mike] I don't
think that that's it.
- [Crow] Administration.
(doors creaking and closing)
- [Mike] Dear, dear, dear
what are we gonna do?
- Whoa, whoa, whoa Mike a
little help here please?
- Yeah, Mike slight
problem here.
- We went and pre-sold
a series of calendars
featuring the hunks and babes
of the hit film "Gorgo."
- Yeah, sold it to
a New Jersey firm,
rough-looking guys and
dark late model cars.
- The mob?
- Right, the mob.
- The mob.
- The mob, exactly.
Well, we filled out
our hunk calender
with that William Frawley guy
you seemed to like so much.
- We had no idea
there wouldn't be
a single woman in
the whole movie.
- Right, now
there's the problem.
Save our lives.
- Okay.
Save your lives.
Well, there are women in
the film, I know that.
I'm just not sure
they have the sizzle
for your mob calender.
- Hell, we'll take
what we can get here.
- All right well Cambot,
let's have a look
at the monitor there.
If I'm not mistaken,
when the two guys
are getting off the
boat in Ireland,
I believe there was a
woman standing right there.
Can we look at that?
- I think you're right.
Hey.
- Whoa, hey, yeah.
- Yeah, there you go.
I'm not sure she's featured
in the film, however.
- Not a problem.
We airbrush out any
blemishes, clip her out
and put her on the hood of a
Lamborghini, we got Miss July.
- Right.
- Next.
- Oh, okay.
Gorgo's chasing people
through the streets.
Bunch of crowd scenes there.
I think there's a woman there.
Cambot, can we fast
forward to that?
There.
- Perfect.
Change her hair, put her
in front of a fireplace
at a rugged lodge,
we got a best seller.
- Ka-ching.
- Guys are on your way, okay.
Well, back to you,
Leonard Maltin.
- Why aren't they suffering?
What's the deal, Leo?
- I don't understand it.
In many cases,
"Gorgo" has been known
to induce hallucinations
and mild drooling,
at the very least.
- Well, you better
start understanding.
I want the worst
movie ever made,
and I want it now, Rex Reed.
- Just hold your water.
Let me see.
I want to hurt 'em
as much as you do.
There's gotta be something
really bad, worst movie.
I would think of something with
Mickey Rourke, wouldn't you?
- Yeah, yeah, yeah
now you're talking.
Cross-reference that
with Eric Roberts,
and we're in business.
You're dead, Nelson.
- Yeah, I think so.
You know, using my new
updated movie and video guide,
we'll find the worst movie ever,
and then, it's curtains for you.
- What did you
say your name was?
- Maltin, Leonard Maltin.
- I like you, Leonard.
(both laughing)
(solemn music)
(man shouting indistinctly)